Guide to The Leo Deaner Radical Left-Wing Publications collection, 1890-2017 LAC0011
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Pamphlets by topic, 1890-2017; Series 3
  - Organizations, 1919-2017; Series 3 Subseries 1
    - Organizations, 1976-1978; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 95, Folder 5)
      On the Question of War: Article from Toufan, Monthly Journal of the Workers and Peasants Communist Party of Iran, vol. 4, no. 5 (March 1978); UNITA: Angola's National Liberation Struggle Through 1976; In the Light of the Ideas of the 7th Congress of the Party of Labour of Albania; Social-Democratic Congress of the French Revisioinists: Editorial of Zeri i Popullit … 21 February, 1976; Report to the Internationalist Rally Welcoming and Closing Remarks Delivered by Comrade Hardial Bains on Behalf of the Communist Party of Canada (Marxist-Leninist) …April 30 and May 1, 1978; Who Will Win in Congo-Kinshasa? By Kibwe Tcha-Malenge; Time for Azania: from the PAC in Perspective Series; Basic Understanding of the Communist Party of China, Shanghai 1974; UNITA: the People's Struggle Until Victory Issued by UNITA's Observer Mission to the United Nations
    - Organizations, 1970-2007; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 95, Folder 6)
      Contents in folder include publications about Venceremos Brigade
      Democracy in Cuba Published by Educational Commission of the Venceremos Brigade; Join the International Feminist Brigade to Cuba in September 1997 [flyer]; Verceremos Brigade, 1975; Brigada Venceremos; Venceremos Brigade Visits Orieints; Cuban Union Leaders Speak: U.S./Cuba Labor Exchange, a Project of the Venceremos Brigade and Venceremos Brigade San Francisco Bay Area Regional; Information Sheet for Brigade Members; Venceremos: a Publication of the Venceremos Brigade, no. 7 (August 1974); Venceremos Brigade … Information on the Venceremos Brigade's Trips to Cuba
    - Organizations, 1937-1980; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 99, Folder 1)
      Contents in folder include publications about Abraham Lincoln Brigade
      For Valor in Battle by Joseph North; Is it Subversive to be Anti-Franco? Published by Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Birgade; Volunteer for Liberty, vol. 3, no. 7 (1942); Volunteer for Liberty (Nov.-Dec. 1943); Fascist Spain America's Enemy by David McKelvy White; Pollitt Visits Spain: Harry Pollitt's Story of his Visit to Spain in December 1937; Brigadas Internacionales: Abraham Lincoln Brigade 1937-1967; Spain and Vietnam: the Fight for Freedom by Robert Colodny Published by Veterans of the Lincoln Brigade; Take no risoners by Ray Durem (Heritage Series v. 17); "Jews in the International Brigades by Albert Prago" in Jewish Currents (February 1979); "Jews in the International Brigades: 2 by Alberto Prago" in Jewish Currents (March 1979); "Readers' Forum on Jews in International Brigades by Alvah Bessie, Albert Prago, Morris U. Schappes" in Jewish Currents (February 1980)
    - Organizations, 1980-1986; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 99, Folder 2)
      43rd (1980), 44th (1981), 46th (1983), 48th (1985), 50th (1986), 51st (1988), 52nd (1989) Anniversary Programs of Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, Bay Area Post; Manchester Men who Fought in Spain by George Brown; Yo Vivi el Drama de la Guerra Civil Espanola by Andres Garcia Suarez; I claim also to be a veteran of the are in Spain by Sister Benedicta, O.S. H.; The Volunteer Published as a Public Service by the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, March 1977, 1982, vol. 5, no, 2 (June 1983), vol. 8, no, 2 (October 1986), vol. 9, no. 3 (November 1987); No Pasaran! The 50th Anniversary of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Published by the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives; 1936-1986: Commemorate the 50th Anniversary of the Spanish Civil War [flyer]
    - Organizations, 1990-2000; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 99, Folder 3)
      54th (1991), 55th (1992), 56th (1993), 57th (1994), 58th (1995) 59th (1996) Anniversary Programs of Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, Bay Area Post; 60th Anniversary of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 1936-1996: Commemorative Program Book Published by Bay Area Post of the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade; Bay Area of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Remember Paul Robeson Commemorative Program; Shouts from the Wall: Posters and Photographs Brought Home from the Spanish Civil War by American Volunteers, Essay by Cary Nelson; Militant Tradition: Commemorating Canadian Volunteers of the International Brigade (Anti-Fascist Forum); 1936-2000 Bay Area Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade: We Must Remember [program]; In Madrid and Mississippi: Volunteers for Liberty: Bay Area Post of the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Celebrate the 40th Anniversary of the Freedom Rides
    - Organizations, 1973-1978; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 99, Folder 4)
      Contents in folder include publications by Marxist-Leninist Organizations
      On Strikes V.I. Lenin Published by Marxist-Leninist Collective; On our Errors: a Fresh Start for Marxist Theory by North Jersey Political Collective; Our Tasks on the National Question: Against Nationalist Deviations in our Movement; All for One, One for All! Socialism in Albania Written by the Central Committee of the Marxist-Leninist Organizing Committee; Proletarian Revolution and the split in the Working Class by the Marxist-Leninist Collective; Organize! Journal of the Trade Union Commission of the Marxist-Leninist Organizing Committee (July 1978); Unite! Marxist-Leninist Organizing Committee, vol. 1, no. 1 (August 1975); Communist Line: Theoretical Journal of the Marxist-Leninist Organizing Committee, no. 2 (October 1, 1975), no. 4 (March 5, 1976), no. 9 (August 1, 1976)
    - Organizations, 1977-1998; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 99, Folder 5)
      Forward: Communist Workers Group (Marxist-Leninist) no. 2 (January 1977), Strike Bulletin by Ad Hoc Strike Committee, San Francisco, no. 2 (February 24, 1978), no. 3 (March 5, 1978), no. 9 (March 7, 1978), no. 11 (March 9, 1978); Workers' Press: the Political Organ of the Marxist-Leninist Collective, vol. 3, no. 12 (December 1977),, [March 1978?]; MLP: Long March to Oblivion; Chile by Revolutionary Marxist Collective (Berkeley-San Francisco); Afro-American National Question, vol. 2 by Communist Workers Party, USA; Class Line: Journal of the Marxist Workers' Group, no. 1 (Spring 1998)
    - Organizations, 1969-1993; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 101, Folder 1)
      Step Forward Towards our Multi-National Communist Party: the Black Study Group Dissolves and Comes Under the Direction of the CCL(ML) Published by the Canadian Communist League (Marxist-Leninist); Briggs & Stratton's Untold Story: Those who Work, Those who Rule Published by the Milwaukee Research Group; Red Desert Bulletin: Official Bulletin of the Tucson Marxist-Leninist Collective, September 1978; Black Nation, 1993 Edition of the classic 1979 Essay by the Afro-American Commission of the Revolutionary Communist League (MLM); Guns & Politics by Will B. Outlaw; New Dawn: News-monthly of the J-Town Collective, vol. 6, no. 7 (August 1976); Insurgent Worker Issued by Sojourner Truth Organization, July 1973; Appendix to A Critique of the Northern California Alliance Written by one of its Authors; Revolutionary Cause: Political Organ of the August 29th Movement (Marxist-Leninist) vol. 2, no. 5 (August 1977); Building the New Communist Party, Guardian Special Supplement, June 1977; Feminism: a Marxist Critique Published by Movement for a Revolutionary Left; Confronting Reality/Learning from the History of Our Movement Published by Bay Area Socialist Organizing Committee; American Communist: Organ of the American Communist Movement. International Solidarity Issue; Workers' Tribune: Organ of the Marxist-Leninist Organization of the USA
    - Organizations, 1951-2014; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 101, Folder 2)
      Contents in folder include Teamster publications:
      Hoffa: Relevant Instructional Materials by Larry Stevens; What Automation Means to You: a Summary of the Effects of the Second Industrial Revolution on the American Worker by Abraham Weiss; Witch Hunt in Minnesota Published by Civil Rights Defense Committee; Behind the 544 Suit Published by the Northwest Organizer, Official Organ of the Minnesota Teamsters Joint Council; Teamsters Union Today: the Impact of a New Leadership and a Fighting Mood, Updated and Expanded Version of 1994 Pamphlet; Some Notes for Trade Union Organizers Published by the Central Conference of Teamsters; Lyndon LaRouche and the New American Fascism by Dennis King, [Xerox copy of p. [333]-368]; Red Teamsters by Bryan D. Palmer; Free Hoffa Petition Sponsored by Michigan State Building and Construction Trades Council
    - Organizations, 1947-1973; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 101, Folder 3)
      Contents in folder include Union of Electrical, Radio & Mechanical Workers publications:
      UE Members Run this Union by James J. Matles; FDR Anniversary Issue, UE Steward, vol. 6, no. 4 (April 1953); Little bit of UE History You Should Know: Remarks of UE President Albert J. Fitzgerald… to 33rd UE International Convention Sept. 9-13, 1968; Proud Record of an American Union: UE; Your Right to Join UE s Guaranteed by Law; Young Worker challenges the Union Establishment; Democracy vs Force and Violence!; Record of UE Gains; 35 Years of Gains in GE; 40 Years of Gains in GE; UE Roosevelt Memorial Broadcast, April 11, 1949; How to Improve your Figure Without Going on a Diet: Vote UE [flyer]; What Happens to your Dues Dollar? [flyer]; How Foreign is Foreign Competition? [flyer]; Organized Labor and the Black Worker Published by United Electrical, Radio & Machine Workers of America (UE); UE's Program for Westinghouse Sunnyvale; UE Westinghouse Organizing Committee Why
    - Organizations, 1961-1977; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 101, Folder 4)
      Contents in folder include Longshoremen publications:
      Longshore Victory, Oct. 1972, December 1972, February 1973; Waterfront worker = Obrero del Astillero, no. 2 (Jan. 28, 1975), no. 4 (Mar. 17, 1975), no. 5 (April 23, 1975); Committee for Justice for Domingo and Viernes; Cultural Evening Legal Update the Committee for Justice for Domingo and Viernes [flyer]; End Nixon's Repression! End Nixon's War! [flyer]; Conspiracy to Defraud the People of the United States; Second ILWU Overseas Report to the 15th Biennial Convention of the International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, April 1-5, 1963; ILWU Story: Three Decades of Militant Unionism; ILWU Story: Sic Decades of Militant Unionism; Longshore Jobs Defense Committee [flyer] L.C.R.C. Bulletin (Longshore Casual Rights Committee)
    - Organizations, 1976-1996; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 101, Folder 5)
      New Unionism and the Trade Union Action League; Trade Union Action League: Workers Unity Against Bosses and Bureaucrats; U.S. Marxist-Leninists, Unite in Struggle Against Social-Chauvinism, and Proletarian Revolution in the U.S. is our Sacred Internationalist Duty! Published by Central Organization of U.S. Marxist-Leninists; Against Social-Democratic Infiltration of the Marxist-Leninist Movement: a Study of the Origin, History and Present Role of the Social-Democrat Barry Weisberg and his MLOC/CPUSA (M-L) Published by Central Organization of U.S. Marxist-Leninists; Announcing the Publication of Imperialist War and Proletarian Civil War by the Organization for a Marxist-Leninist Workers' Party, U.S.A.; History of the Afro-American People's Struggle in Seattle by the Seattle Branch, Central Organization of U.S. Marxist-Leninists; Workers' Advocate Reprint: Resist the Outrageous Robbery of the Masses by the U.S. Oil Monopolies!; Chicago Workers' Voice: Theoretical Journal Issue Published by the Chicago Workers' Voice, no,. 4 (Sept. 1994), no. 7 (May 25, 1995), no. 9 (Jan. 29, 1996); March 8 International Working Women's Day Published Jointly by Trade Union Action League, Liberation League, and Revolutionary Political Organization (Marxist-Leninist); Advance: Newsletter of the Trade Union Action League, National Organizing Committee vol. 1, no., 2 (August 1980), vol. 1, no, 3 (September 1980), vol. 1, no, 4 (November 1980), vol. 2, no, 2 (March 1981); Advance: Official Newspaper of the Trade Union Action League vol. 2, no, 4 (August/Sept. 1981), vol. 5, no. 4 (May-June 1984), vol. 5, no, 7 (September/October 1984)
    - Organizations, 1941-1969; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 102, Folder 1)
      Contents in folder include publications about Socialist Labor Party
      Fifty Years of American Marxism 1891-1941, Commemorating the 50th Anniversary of the Founding of the Weekly People Published by the Socialist Labor Party; Socialist Labor Party 1890-1930: During Four Decades by Henry Kuhn and Olive M. Johnson
    - Organizations, 1971; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 102, Folder 2)
      Contents in folder include publications about Spartacist Movement
      Fight the Betrayers, Workers Vanguard Supplement 13 Oct. 1971 by Spartacist League
    - Organizations, 1972; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 102, Folder 3)
      Contents in folder include publications about Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workers
      Union of Big Shoulders 75: Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America AFL-CIO
    - Organizations, 1972-2000; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 102, Folder 4)
      Contents in folder include publications about Communist Labor Party
      Documents Second Party Congress of the Communist Labor Party of the United States of North America, November 1975; Fight for Jobs Published by Communist Labor Party of the United States of North America (C.L.P.U.S.N.A.); Moving Onward from Racial Division to Class Unity by Brooke Heagerty and Nelson Peery; Negro National Colonial Question by Nelson Peery; Progressive workers' Circuit: Issued by Members of the Communist Labor Party and other Workers at GTE-LENKURT, vol. 1, no. 2 (February 1976); Negro National Colonial Question by the Communist League
    - Organizations, 1976-1991; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 102, Folder 5)
      Entering an Epoch of Social Revolution by Nelson Perry; Modern-Day Slave Ship: Immigration Law; Last Hired, First Fired: From the Pages of the People's Tribune; Struggle for the Liberation of Angola Prepared by the Angola Research Committee for the Communist Labor Party of the USA; Deadly Business: Weapons and Wall Street; No Nukes, No War by Steven Miller; Road to Socialism: Documents 3rd Congress, Communist Labor Party, November 1980; Documents of the 5th Congress, Communist Labor Party, April 1991; Vanguard Books Catalogue 1977; Jobs, Peace, Equality, the Communist Labor Party; Proletariat: a Theoretical Journal Published by the Communist Labor Party USNA, vol. 1, no. 1 (January 1975); Proletariat 1 (June 1987)
    - Organizations, 1973-1982; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 102, Folder 6)
      Contents in folder include publications about Revolutionary Communist Party
      New Programme and New Constitution of the Revolutionary Communist Party, USA: Drafts for Discussion 1980; If there is to be a Revolution, There must be a Revolutionary Party by Bob Avakian; Coming from Behind to Make Revolution: Talk by Bob Avakian, Chairman of the Central Committee of the Revolutionary Communist Party, USA; Tasks of Party Branches, the Task of Revolution by the Revolutionary Communist Party, USA, Reprinted from Revolution; Workers' History Calendar 1973; Workers' History Calendar 1974; On Building the Party of the U.S. Working Class and the Struggle Against Dogmatism and Reformism: Speeches by Bob Avakian, Member of the Central Committee of the Revolutionary Union; The Worker Special National Edition for July 4; Basic Principles for the Unity of Marxist-Leninists and for the Line of the International Communist Movement: Draft Paper for Discussion Prepared by the Revolutionary Communist Party of Chile and the Revolutionary Communist Party, USA
    - Organizations, 1973-1976; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 102, Folder 7)
      Contents in folder include publications about Workers' Committee
      Introduction [to] Workers' Committee; On the Line Published Monthly by the Seacoast Area Workers' Committee, vol. 3, no. 8 (August 1973), vol. 4, no. 2 (February 1974), vol. 4, no. 7 (Aug 1974), vol. 5, no, 3 (March 1975), vol. 5, no 4 (April 1975), vol. 5, no. 6 (May 1975); [Notes on how Seacoast Area Workers' Committee started]; Worker for the New EnglandArea, vol. 1, no 9 (July 1976), vol. 1, no. 12 (September 1976); Building Unemployment Work
    - Organizations, 1973-2002; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 102, Folder 8)
      Contents in folder include publications about Black Liberation Movement
      Message to the Black Movement: a Political State from the Black Underground Coordinating Committee, Black Liberation Army, CC-BLA; Interview with Assata Shakur; Bring the Are Home: Forgotten Heros [sic], vol. 1 by Black Liberation Army and the Weather Underground; Political Conviction of R. Dhoruba Moor and the Repression of the Black Liberation Movement by the International Committee to Free Dhoruba Moor; Stop the Conspiracy Trial and all FBI Attacks on the New Afrikan Independence Movement Demonstrate Monday, April 25… Sponsored by the John Brown Anti-Klan Committee [flyer]
    - Organizations, 1968-1979; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 102, Folder 9)
      Contents in folder include publications about Uhuru Movement
      Black Artists Everywhere Published in Uhuru, the Freedom Magazine, vol. 1, no. 5 (March 1968); Join the Sustainer Drive Issued by International People's Democratic UHURU Movement [3 flyers]; Defend the National Democratic Rights of the African Community: Join Friends of Uhuru House Issued by African People's Solidarity Committee; Save Oakland from the Latest Scheme by Uhuru House, Join Oakland's Elected Leaders and Concerned Citizens: Vote No on "H"; Home is Where the Soul is by Jon Eckles; Racism in the Women's Movement: Liberation or White Rights? [flyer]; Walk Against Genocide Reparations for African People Now! June 5 [flyer]
    - Organizations, 1940; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 108, Folder 1)
      Contents in folder includes publication about Trade Unions
      Labor Day 1940: Supplement to Union Labor News, Official Organ of Santa Maria-San Luis Obispo Building Trades Council, Santa Maria Central Labor council, San Luis Obispo Central Labor Council
    - Organizations, 1950; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 108, Folder 2)
      Contents in folder includes publication about ILGWU
      ILGWU News-History 1900-1950: the Story of the Ladies' Garment Workers, ILGWU Golden Jubilee Convention, Atlantic City, N.J., May 1950
    - Organizations, Undated; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 108, Folder 5)
      Contents in this folder relate to Steelworkers
      Rivers of Steel.
    - Organizations, 1901-1964; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 109, Folder 1)
      Contents in folder include publications about AFL-CIO
      Union Label: Its History and Aims Prize Essays Published by American Federation of Labor; Discrimination Costs you Money Published by National Labor Service; Extremists Published by AFL-CIO Committee on Political Education; American Labor Looks at the World Published by International Labor Relations Department, American Federation of Labor; Tent City: Home of the Brave Published by Industrial Union Department, AFL-CIO; Automation's Unkept Promise Published by Industrial Union Department, AFL-CIO; Secretary's Report to the Officers and Delegates of the21st Annual Convention of the American Federation of Labor; Taxation …the Key to Mass Buying Power and Full Employment in an Expanding Economy by Walter P. Reuther, Excerpts from Testimony on HR 8300 before the Committee on Finance, United States Senate, April 13, 1954
    - Organizations, 1935-1973; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 109, Folder 2)
      CIO Servicemen's Manual Published by National CIO Committee for American and Allied War Relief; Jobs, Peace, Unity by John L. Lewis Published by CIO; Industrial Democracy by John L. Lewis (CIO Publication no. 9 (Jan. 1937)); Labor and the Nation by John L. Lewis (CIO Publication no. 10 (Sept. 1937)); As we Win Published by CIO Post-War Planning Committee (CIO Publication no. 98); Allied Labor Unity Vital to Victory Now: an Address Delivered at the 1942 A.F.of L. Convention in Toronto by Jack Tanner Issued by Committee of A.F. of L. Trade Unionists to Promote Unity of the United Nations Trade Union Movement; Future of Organized Labor by John L. Lewis Published by Committee for Industrial Organization; Values we Cherish by Walter P. Reuther Published by Industrial Union Department, AFL-CIO; John L: Lewis: Labor's Strong Willed Organizer by Gerald Kurland (Outstanding Personalities no. 56); John L. Lewis, Francis Gorman … at 55th Annual Convention American Federation of Labor, Atlantic City, October 1935; Auto Rank and File Hail Mr. Organized Labor Published by Local 60, United Auto Workers; To Abolish Discrimination Published by National CIO Committee to Abolish Discrimination; Where is the CIO Going? a Program for Militant Trade Unionism by George Morris; CIO and the Negro Worker Together for Victory by Congress of Industrial Organizations; Industrial Unions and Taft-Hartley Published by Industrial Union Department, AFL-CIO; We Shall March Together: Two Statements by Walter P. Reuther (CIO Pamphlet no. 216); Time to get Angry: a Counter-Offensive to the Attack on American Education by James B. Carey (CIO Pamphlet no. 230); New Beginning: an Address by Walter P. Reuther to the CIO Executive Board, February 24, 1955 (CIO Pamphlet no. 268); Teaching Guide for AFL-CIO Stewards: Instructions and Suggestions for a 6-Session Course Published by AFL-CIO Department of Education
    - Organizatons, 1964-1969; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 109, Folder 3)
      Port Huron Statement Issued by Students for a Democratic Society; Student Social Action by Tm Hayden Distributed by Students for a Democratic Society; Cuba vs. U.S. Imperialism Published by SDA; Cuba: a History 1868-1959 Published by SDS;SDS Plans for American High Schools: Report of the Committee on Internal Security, House of Representatives, 91st Congress, 1st Session; Working Papers Summer Projects by Paul Booth Issued by SDS; New Left Today, or Two Years of the New Era by Jim Williams (SDS National Convention Working Paper); New Left Manifesto by Paul Booth and Edward Greer. Draft Issued by Students for Democratic Society
    - Organizations, 1940-1973; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 109, Folder 4)
      Contents in folder include publications about Trade Unions
      Politics of Health Care: a Bibliography Edited by Ken Rosenberg & Gordon Schiff, Boston Medical Committee for Human Rights; Hospital Workers; the Best Contract Anywhere? Inside the Hospital Workers' Union by Elinor Langer; Heywood Broun as He Seemed to Us by John L. Lewis [et al] Published for the Newspaper Guild of New York
    - Organizations, 1935-1982; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 109, Folder 5)